sitebuilder.vpweb.com 2015-12-31

# Vistaprint Privacy & Security

Vistaprint.com Privacy Policy

Vistaprint values your privacy and appreciates your trust in us. This Privacy Policy explains how we use, share and protect the personally identifiable information that we collect about you (“Personal Information”) and the choices you have. This Privacy Policy applies to visitors to www.vistaprint.com (“Website”) and to our online customers. By visiting or using our Website, you agree to this Privacy Policy. 

This Privacy Policy does not apply to information about you collected by our affiliates or third party websites that may post links or advertisements on or otherwise be accessible from the Website. The information collected by these affiliates or third party websites is subject to their own privacy policies. 

At Vistaprint we use cookies to: keep track of what items you have in your basket, remember you when you return to our website and to improve your experience on our website. For example, cookies allow us to recall your past activities and site preferences, tailor parts of our website to your needs and make special offers to you, as well as identify and resolve errors. 

We would like to point out that cookies don't harm your device. We do not usually store your sensitive or personally identifiable information in cookies we create. If we do, we obtained that information from you directly as you would have provided it to us via our website and we only use it for the purposes outlined in this Cookies and Privacy Policy. All the information we gather from cookies is secure. 

We also work with selected third party companies who may also set cookies on your device during your visit to our website. They use the information collected from their cookies to serve ads to you on different products and services based on what you may be interested in. They may also use cookies to track your response to their ad, to measure the effectiveness of their advertising or to award incentives or points to their members who respond to their ads. 

It’s important for you to know that we have no access to, or control over cookies used by our selected third party companies. We do not share any of your personally identifiable information such as your name, telephone number or address with these companies, except in accordance with our Privacy Policy. 

If you have purchased a website through Vistaprint, we only use one cookie on Vistaprint hosted websites. We use this cookie to count the number of unique visitors, so we know how many people visit the websites we host and to report that to you via your website dashboard. This cookie is not used for anything else beyond this. It does not use or store any personally identifiable information and other companies who provide websites like us, also use similar types of cookies on their customers websites. For more information on how to manage cookies on your Vistaprint website click on this link – 

Cookies and my Vistaprint website

Information We Collect

We collect a variety of information from our customers and visitors to the Website. As described below, some information is automatically collected when you visit our Website or purchase something, and some you provide to us when registering or filling out a form, buying a product or service or communicating with us. We may also acquire information from third parties. 

Information Collected Automatically: Whenever you visit our Website, we automatically collect some information about your transactions with us, and your use of our Website. For example, we automatically collect your IP address, the type of operating system and web browser you use and related information. We also automatically track certain information about your activities on our Website such as the pages you visit. If you are a registered Vistaprint customer, we link this automatically-collected data to the Personal Information we collect to help us customize your experience on our Website and improve our service to you. 

Information You Provide Us: If you provide us with Personal Information by filling out a form, registering for an account, making a purchase or contacting us, we collect that Personal Information. For example, if you register on our Website, we collect your name, e-mail address and password. If you place an order with us, we collect the Personal Information that you provide to us such as your shipping, billing, and payment information. You may also have the option to store credit card or other payment information to make it easier to purchase products or service from the Website in the future. If you design and personalize a product, such as a business card, we collect the Personal Information you use to customize the product, such as the name of your business or your professional title. If you contact our customer services agents, you may also provide us with Personal Information that we collect. 

From time-to-time, Vistaprint may give you the opportunity to participate in sweepstakes, contests or surveys on our Website. If you participate, we will collect certain Personal Information from you. Participation in these sweepstakes, surveys or contests is completely voluntary and you therefore have a choice whether or not to disclose the requested information. 

Information about Your Transactions with Us: When you purchase a product or service, we collect all of your order information, such as the type of product you purchased and the costs of each product. 

Reviews and Public Forums: We may provide you with the opportunity to review our products or participate in public forums associated with the Website. Any reviews, posts or comments will be public so you should use care before posting information about yourself online. 

Additional Information We Collect: From time to time, we may acquire additional information about our customers from third parties, such as the U.S. Postal Service. We may incorporate this additional information with the existing information we collect about our customers. 

Where we Process and Store Data: Vistaprint processes and stores data in Devonshire, Bermuda and in other locations for back-up and recovery purposes or to enable us to offer you certain services. Depending on where you are located, Bermuda and the other jurisdictions where we store data may not have data protection laws that provide an equivalent level of protection to the laws in your home country or jurisdiction. By using the Website and providing us with your Personal Information, you are consenting to the transfer and processing of your Personal Information in jurisdictions outside of your home country or jurisdiction. 

Cookies and Similar Files

Our Website uses “cookies” and files that are similar to cookies. Cookies are alphanumeric identifiers created by your browser at our request and stored on your computer. When the cookie is stored on your computer, Vistaprint assigns you a unique customer code. When you return to our Website, we read the cookie to identify you as one of our customers and help recall orders or preferences you have selected. The cookie also enables us to recall your past activities, post your account data, and tailor site elements and special offers to you. No Personal Information about you is stored on the cookie. 

Most Web browsers accept cookies by default, but allow users to reject cookies by changing the browser preferences. If you have set up your browser to reject cookies or if you delete your cookies, some aspects of our Website, including our Shopping Cart, will not work properly.

We also use ETags to store a unique customer code in the cache of your browser that allows us to identify you when you return to the Website. The ETag allows us to tailor the Website and recall your preferences and past orders. No Personal Information about you is stored in the ETag. Clearing your browsers cache will delete any ETags. 

If you have Adobe’s Macromedia Flash installed on your computer, we will also use a file called a Flash Object to store a unique customer code on your computer. Unless deactivated by you, the Flash Object provides us with a backup method for recognizing you and tailoring your experience on our Website in the event that we are unable to identify your cookies. Flash Objects are stored separately from cookies and not all browsers delete Flash Objects when you delete cookies. You can learn more about Flash Objects and how to disable them by going to this page on the Adobe website: <http://kb2.adobe.com/cps/526/52697ee8.html>. 

If you receive emails from Vistaprint, we may use Web Beacons and similar technologies allow us to track whether you have opened the message and whether you have clicked on links contained in the message. 

We use third-party advertising companies to serve advertisements on our behalf. These companies may use a cookie or an action tag, also known as a Web Beacon or a 1 pixel .gif file, to tailor the advertisements you see on this Website and other sites, to track your response to their advertisement and to measure the effectiveness of their advertising or to award incentives or points to their members who respond to their advertisements. We also provide these companies with Personal Information to help them serve more relevant advertisements for our and other companies’ products. The cookies, action tags or similar files do not contain any Personal Information. 

You can learn more about targeted advertising, its benefits and your choices by going to <http://www.aboutads.info/consumers/>. The targeted advertising companies we work with are members of the Network Advertising Initiative. The NAI allows you to limit targeted advertising from its members by using an opt-out tool available on the NAI website at <http://www.networkadvertising.org/consumer/opt_out.asp>. 

This Privacy Policy covers the use of cookies, Flash Objects, ETags and similar files by Vistaprint only and does not cover the use of cookies, Flash Objects, ETags and similar files by any third party advertisers or websites linked to the Website. 

Use and Disclosure of Information

We use the information that we collect about you to maintain, improve, and administer our Website, operate our business, provide products and services that you request, administer your account, inform you about products and services that might be of interest to you, and personalize your online experience. 

Business Operations: In order to carry out certain business functions, such as order fulfillment, payment processing, e-mail delivery, or marketing, we sometimes hire other companies to perform services on our behalf. We may disclose Personal Information that we collect about you to these companies to enable them to perform these services. 

Communicating with You: We use Personal Information to communicate with you about your order, remind you of orders you have pending and other transactional or administrative updates as well as to send you offers for products and services that may be of interest to you. 

Third Party Offers: We partner with third parties to provide you with products or services that may be of interest to you. When we do so, we may share, rent or sell your name, mailing address, phone number and information about your use of the Website and the types of products you have purchased or are interested in. We do not share, rent or sell your email address without your explicit consent. 

From time to time, we may send you offers on behalf of third parties or promote such offers on our Website. We do not share any Personal Information with the third party, unless you accept the offer or request additional information about the offer. If you do accept a third party offer or request additional information, we may share Personal Information with the third party and they may collect other Personal Information directly from you. In addition, if you accept a co-branded offer presented by Vistaprint and another company, any Personal Information you provide will be collected by both Vistaprint and the third party. Once a third party has your Personal Information, it is governed by the third party’s privacy policy. 

As describe in more detail in the “Your Choices” section below, you can review and update your marketing preferences in the My Account section of the Website. 

Law Enforcement, Protection of Vistaprint and our Customers: We may also disclose Personal Information in other circumstances as required by law. We also reserve the right to disclose your Personal Information when we believe such disclosure is appropriate to cooperate with an investigation of activities claimed to be unlawful, to enforce our Terms of Use, or to protect the rights or property of Vistaprint or others. 

Merger, Sale or Acquisition: In addition, it is possible that in the future another company may acquire Vistaprint or its assets or that Vistaprint may partner with or purchase another company to continue to do business as a combined entity. In the event that any such transaction occurs, it is possible that our customer information, including your Personal Information, may be transferred to the new business entity as one of Vistaprint’s assets. In such an event, we will update this policy to reflect any change in ownership or control of your Personal Information. 

Links to Third Party Products and Services

While you are visiting or using the Website, you may be presented with an opportunity to purchase third party products or services. These products and services are offered and supplied by independent companies. If you click on one of the presented offers, you will be redirected to the site of the third party, and any information you provide in response to the offer will be will be governed by the privacy and other policies of that third party. 

Your Choices

We offer you a variety of choices with respect to how we use and share your Personal Information. 

Sharing Information with Others for Marketing Purposes: If you do not want Vistaprint to share your Personal Information with third parties for their own marketing purposes, you can update your preferences by going to the My Account section of the Website or by sending a written request to the address below. If you send a written request, please be sure to include your exact name, mailing address and telephone number(s) and a statement that you would like us not to share your Personal Information with other organizations that may have special offers, products or services that may be of interest to you. Even if you do opt-out of this sharing, we may still share Personal Information about you as required by law or to carry out certain business operations, as described above, or if you purchase a product or service from a third party or request additional information about such a product or service. 

Communications from Vistaprint: If you do not want to receive email communications from Vistaprint about our own or third-party products and services that may be of interest to you, you can update your preferences in the My Account section of the Website. You can also click on the unsubscribe link at the bottom of one of our emails. We may still contact you via mail or phone, unless you request to be added to our Do-Not-Call list, and/or our Do-Not-Mail list by writing to the address below and indicating your preferences. Please be sure to provide your exact name, e-mail address, mailing address and telephone number(s) and the list or lists you would like to be included on (Do-Not-Call, and/or Do-Not-Mail). Even if you opt-out of email marketing or choose to be placed on one of these lists, we may still communicate with you using any of these methods regarding your use of our Website, your orders or your account, or for similar transactional or administrative reasons. 

Deactivation of Your Account: You may also request deactivation of your Vistaprint account by contacting Customer Service at customercare@vistaprint.com or by writing to the address below and requesting account deactivation. Please note that your Personal Information may remain in our archived records after your account has been deactivated. 

Updating Your Personal Information

If you wish to change your name, e-mail address, password, and/or communication preferences after you have registered, you can access your account in the My Account section of the Website. You may also request these changes by contacting Customer Service or calling Customer Service at 1.866.614.8002 or writing to the address below. 

_Vistaprint Limited  
c/o Vistaprint USA Incorporated  
Customer Care  
275 Wyman Street  
Waltham Ma 02451  
USA  
Copy Text to Clipboard   
Vistaprint Limited  
c/o Vistaprint USA Incorporated  
Customer Care  
95 Hayden Avenue  
Lexington MA 02421  
USA  

Website Security

We maintain reasonable physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards designed to help us protect your nonpublic Personal Information against loss, misuse, disclosure and alteration. For example, we use Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology to encrypt your credit card information when you purchase products through our Website. 

When you establish an account at Vistaprint, you choose a password to help protect your account information. A password is only as strong as you make it: you should select a unique password and keep it safe. You may change your password as often as you wish by going to My Account section of the Website. 

Changes to this Privacy Policy

Vistaprint may revise this Privacy Policy from time to time by posting a revised Privacy Policy on our Website and changing the last modified date at the top of the Privacy Policy. If we make significant changes to the Privacy Policy, we will note the Privacy Policy has changed on the main page of the Website. We reserve the right to modify this Privacy Policy at any time, so please review it frequently. 

Vistaprint Address for Written Requests

Written request may be sent to the following address. When writing to us, please be sure to include your exact name, mailing address, telephone number and specific preferences or request. 

Vistaprint Netherlands B.V.  
c/o _[LM:SiteBranding:CompanyName]_ USA, Incorporated  
Customer Service  
275 Wyman Street  
WalthamMA 02451  
USA 

Special Notification for California Residents

Individual customers who reside in California and have provided their Personal Information to Vistaprint may request information about our disclosures of certain categories of Personal Information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. Such requests must be submitted to us in writing at the address below. 

This request may be made no more than once per calendar year. We reserve our right not to respond to requests submitted other than to the address specified below. 

Problems Signing In

Our sign-in process is designed to help protect your privacy. If you have trouble signing in to our Website, please ensure that you are using your registered e-mail address and/or correct password. If you are using your registered e-mail address and correct password, and you continue to have trouble signing in to our site, please contact Customer Service.

Order Confirmation

Vistaprint sends an e-mail notice confirming acceptance of each order you place to the e-mail address you provided to us when signing up for a Vistaprint account. If you receive a confirmation for an order you did not place, please e-mail us immediately at Customer Service.
